veracross.com 2017-07-08

# Privacy Policy - Veracross

#### Protecting Your Private Information is our Priority

**General Information**

For the purposes of this Privacy Policy, unless otherwise noted, all references to Veracross LLC, include “we,” “us,” “our,” Veracross and [www.veracross.com](https://www.veracross.com/). This Privacy Policy applies to [www.veracross.com](https://www.veracross.com/) and Veracross Platform Services and governs data collection and usage. The Veracross website is a site used to provide information about our services. The use of information collected through our service shall be limited to the purpose of providing the service for which the Client has engaged Veracross. 

By accessing and using this Veracross website, you agree that you have read and understand this Privacy Policy and you consent to the privacy practices (and any uses and disclosures of information about you) that are described in this Privacy Policy. Please read this Privacy Policy carefully to understand how we collect, share, and protect information about you. 

Veracross participates in and has certified its compliance with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and the Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework. Veracross is committed to subjecting all personal data received from European Union (EU) member countries and Switzerland, in reliance on the Privacy Shield Framework, to the Framework’s applicable Principles. To learn more about the Privacy Shield Framework, visit the U.S. Department of Commerce’s Privacy Shield List <https://www.privacyshield.gov/list>. 

Veracross is responsible for the processing of personal data it receives, under the Privacy Shield Framework, and subsequently transfers to a third party acting as an agent on its behalf. Veracross complies with the Privacy Shield Principles for all onward transfers of personal data from the EU and Switzerland, including the onward transfer liability provisions. 

With respect to personal data received ** ** or ** ** transferred pursuant to the Privacy Shield Framework, Veracross is subject to the regulatory enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission. In certain situations, Veracross may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements. 

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at <https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request>. 

Under certain conditions, more fully described on the Privacy Shield website [https://www.privacyshield.gov](https://www.privacyshield.gov/), you may invoke binding arbitration when other dispute resolution procedures have been exhausted. 

**Collection of Your Personal Information**

We may collect personally identifiable data, such as: name, e-mail address, mailing address, phone number, or other data required to enable us to provide services you may have requested or contracted us to provide, or on behalf of one of our Clients. We also may collect other identifying information from or about you in connection with your use of this website. For example, we may collect and store the content of, and data regarding, any correspondence you may have with us or our representatives, regardless of the subject matter or the mode of communication by which such correspondence is made. You may, however, visit our public website anonymously. 

As with many other websites, the Internet servers used to operate this website may collect certain information pertaining to you and the software, equipment and communications method that you use to access the Internet and this website. This information can include: IP address, browser type, domain names, access times, and referring website addresses. This information is used for the operation of the service, to maintain quality of the service, and to provide general statistics regarding use of the website. 

**Cookies and other tracking technologies**

Veracross and its partners use cookies or similar technologies to analyze trends, administer the website, track users’ movements around the website, and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. You can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level, but if you choose to disable cookies, it may limit your use of certain features or functions on our website or service. To manage Flash cookies, please click [here](http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager07.html). We use this information, which does not identify individual users, to analyze trends, to administer the site, to track users’ movements around the site, to gather information about our user base as a whole, and to comply with other security requirements that we adhere to. We do not link this automatically-collected data to personally identifiable information. 

**Advertising**

We partner with a third party to display advertising on our website or to manage our advertising on other sites. Our third party partner may use cookies or similar technologies in order to provide you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests. If you wish to opt out of interest-based advertising click [here](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/) or if located in the European Union click here [here](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/). Please note you will continue to receive generic ads. 

**Information Related to Data Collected through the Veracross Platform Service**

Veracross collects information under the direction of contracted educational institutions, and has no direct relationship with the individuals whose personal data it processes. 

**Choice**

The Veracross Platform Service collects information for our Clients; if you are a user of one of our Clients and would no longer like to be contacted by one of our Clients that use our service, please contact the Client that you interact with directly. 

**Service Provider, Sub-Processors/Onward Transfer**

Veracross may transfer personal information to companies that help us provide our service. Transfers to subsequent third parties are covered by the provisions in this policy regarding notice and choice and the service agreements with our Clients. 

Veracross has no direct relationship with the individuals whose personal data it processes through the Veracross Platform Service. An individual who seeks access, or who seeks to correct, amend, or delete inaccurate data should direct their query to the individual Veracross Client. If the Client requests Veracross to remove the data, we will respond to their request within 30 business days. 

**Data Retention**

Veracross will retain personal data we process on behalf of our Clients for as long as needed to provide services to our Client. Veracross will retain and use this personal information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. 

**Testimonials**

We display personal testimonials of satisfied customers on our site in addition to other endorsements. With your consent, we may post your testimonial along with your name. If you wish to update or delete your testimonial, you can contact us at [info@veracross.com](mailto:info@veracross.com). 

**Use of Your Personal Information  
**

We collect and use personal information to operate our website(s), and to deliver the services you have requested or on behalf of our Clients. If you are a direct Client or prospect, we may also use your personally identifiable information to inform you of other products or services available from Veracross. If you are a direct Client, we may also contact you via surveys to conduct research about your opinion of current services or of potential new services that may be offered. The use of information collected through the Veracross Platform Service shall be limited to the purpose of providing the service for which the educational intuition has engaged Veracross. 

We do not sell, rent, or lease customer lists or any of your personally identifiable information to third parties. If you do not want us to share your personal information with these companies, you may contact us at [info@veracross.com](mailto:info@veracross.com). 

If you are a direct Client or prospect, we may share data with trusted partners to help perform statistical analysis, send you email or postal mail, provide customer support, or arrange for deliveries. For certain sensitive information (e.g., personal information specifying medical or health conditions, racial or ethnic origin, or information pertaining to the sex life of an individual), we must obtain your affirmative consent (opt in) before such information may be disclosed to a third party or used for a purpose other than those for which it was originally collected or subsequently authorized by you through the exercise of an opt in choice. All such third parties are prohibited from using your personal information, except to provide these services to Veracross, and they are required to maintain at least the same level of privacy protection that we maintain for your information. 

Veracross will disclose your personal information, without notice, only if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to: (a) conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process, such as a subpoena, served on us or the site; (b) protect and defend our rights or property; (c) act under necessary circumstances to protect the personal safety of users, or the public; and, (d) In certain situations, Veracross may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements. 

If Veracross is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our website of any change in ownership or uses of your personally identifiable information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personally identifiable information. 

**Security of Your Personal Information**

We maintain physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards designed to help secure our platform and your personal information, and to assist us in preventing unauthorized access, use, disclosure, loss, alteration and destruction of that information. When you enter sensitive information or login to our portal, we encrypt the transmission of that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL). Nevertheless, no set of security safeguards is guaranteed to be impenetrable. If you have any questions about the security of your personal information, you can contact us at: [info@veracross.com](mailto:info@veracross.com). 

We cannot and do not guarantee that communications to or from our website, or that data transmitted or stored on or through the website, are or will be totally secure from unauthorized access, use, disclosure, loss, alteration, or destruction by third parties. 

**Children**

Veracross is committed to protecting the privacy of children. This website is not designed or intended to attract anyone under age 18. Veracross does not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under the age of 18 or under the legal age of majority in your jurisdiction. BY ACCESSING THIS WEBSITE, YOU REPRESENT THAT YOU HAVE REACHED THE AGE OF MAJORITY IN YOUR JURISDICTION. 

**Opt-Out & Unsubscribe**

We respect your privacy and give you an opportunity to opt-out of receiving announcements of certain information. Users may opt-out of receiving any or all communications from Veracross pertaining to our public website by contacting us here: 

·       Web page: [www.veracross.com](https://www.veracross.com/)

·       Email: [info@veracross.com](mailto:info@veracross.com)

·       Phone 781.246.0010 

**Member Directory**

Regarding the Veracross Platform Service (and not the Veracross marketing website [www.veracross.com](https://www.veracross.com/)), we may list you in our ”Client-only accessible” member directory. If you are a member and wish to request removal of your information from our directory, you may contact us at [info@veracross.com](mailto:info@veracross.com). 

Upon request Veracross will provide you with information about whether we hold, or process on behalf of a third party, any of your personal information. You may request to review the personal information we maintain about you and correct, amend, or delete that information where it is inaccurate by contacting us using the website, email address, or phone number listed above. We will respond to your request to access within 30 days provided, however, that we shall not be required to do so where, in our reasonable judgment, the burden or expense would be disproportionate to the risks to your privacy in a particular case of where the rights of persons other than you would be violated. 

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active, or as needed, to provide you services. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. 

**Links to Third Party Websites**

We encourage you to review the privacy policies of websites you choose to link to from ours so that you can understand how those websites collect, use, and share your information. We are not responsible for the privacy statements or other content on websites outside of the Veracross website. 

**Social Media**

Our website includes social media features, such as a Facebook button and widgets, the Twitter button or interactive mini-programs that run on our website. These features may collect your IP address, track which pages you are visiting on our website, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Social media features and widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our website. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing these features. 

**Changes to this Policy**

We will occasionally update this Privacy Policy to reflect company and customer feedback. If we make any material changes we will notify you by email, or by means of a notice on this website, prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this policy to be informed of how we are protecting your information. 

**Contact Information**

Veracross welcomes your questions or comments regarding this Privacy Policy. If you believe that we have not adhered to this policy, please contact us at: 

Veracross LLC 

401 Edgewater Place 

Wakefield, Massachusetts 01880 

Email Address: [info@veracross.com](mailto:info@veracross.com)

Telephone number: 781.246.0010 

Effective as of May 9, 2017 

401 Edgewater Place

Suite 360

Wakefield, MA 01880

866.492.3463
